# Raju Maharjan

Technical University of Denmark, Ørsteds Plads, 345B, 258, 2800 Kgs. Lyngby, Denmark maharrx@gmail.com +4591862561 www.rajumaharjan.com

## **PROFILE**

I am a postdoctoral researcher at the Technical University of Denmark, DTU management. My current research focuses on conversational interaction design to improve patients' engagement with an exoskeleton-based stroke rehabilitation system. My research areas of interest include human-centered design, health & wellbeing technologies, conversational agents, and information visualization.

# **EDUCATION**

11/2021	Ph.D., <b>Digital Health Technology</b> , Technical University of Denmark  Title: Speech-Enabled Conversational Agents to Support the Self-Report of Mental Health & Wellbeing
	Supervisors: Jakob E. Bardram & Per Bækgaard
01/2017	MA, Web & Multimedia Design, Touro College, NY
06/2013	BSc, Dynamic Web Design, The Graduate Center, The City University of New York
08/2009	AAS, New Media Technology, LaGuardia Community College, The City University of New York

## **AWARDS & HONORS**

2012 – 2013	$\textbf{Thomas W. Smith Fellowship}, \ The \ City \ University \ of \ New \ York, \ NY$
12/12/2012	Promise Prize, Code for Change, New York University, NY

# **RESEARCH EXPERIENCE**

12/2019 – Present **Postdoctoral Research**, Project ReHyb

This project aims to help the rehabilitation of stroke patients through an exoskeleton system. I am employing strategies of verbal persuasion by integrating speech interaction into the system and investigating its effect on user engagement and motivation to use the system.

08/2019 - 11/2021 **Ph.D. Research**, Project SOFIA

This research project that aims to improve the quality of life of people living with mental illness. As a part of the research, I investigated the feasibility of a speech-enabled conversational agent to support the self-report of mental health and wellbeing by assessing its capacity to accurately capture the wellbeing self-reports in compared to the paper based method, understanding users' perception of the system's usability, and comparing users' engagement and experiences with the agent vs. traditional web-based app.

02/2018 - 07/2019 User Research & System Design, Project mCardia

The goal of this highly interdisciplinary research project was to design, develop, and evaluate the clinical feasibility of a smartphone-based ambulatory heart monitoring system. Adopting the user-centered design approach, I designed the prototype of the mCardia system which included patient-facing mobile app that enabled real-time visualization of the cardiovascular data (e.g., Heart Rate (HR), Heart Rate Variability (HRV), and Electrocardiogram (ECG) data collected via a two-channel Holter device and contextual information such as patient self-reports) and a web application that allowed clinicians to analyze and annotate the ECG data with the contextual information.

# 06/2011 – 01/2012 **Director of Technology**, Artbox

Artbox is an National Science Foundation (NSF)-funded app development project with an aim to create an engaging online community of artists and art enthusiasts. My role was to research mobile technology and propose features to engage a diverse group of users, help them make connections with each other, and encourage them to keep coming back to the app. To do so, we conducted semi-structured interviews with artists and patrons to investigate how they use technology and social media and visited museums, auction houses, and art exhibitions to conceptualize the app's business model.

## **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

Student Supervision, Technical University of Denmark

07/2019 - 12/2019 Chen Wang, MSc, Digital Media Engineering

Teaching Assistant, Technical University of Denmark

01/2019 - 03/2019 Personal Data Interaction for Mobile & Wearables

01/2019 – 01/2019 User Experience Engineering

09/2018 - 11/2018 User Experience Design Prototyping

## **PUBLICATIONS**

#### **Journals**

Raju Maharjan, Kevin Doherty, Darius Adam Rohani, Per Bækgaard, and Jakob E. Bardram. 2021. Experiences of a Speech-Enabled Conversational Agent for the Self-Report of Wellbeing Among People Living with Affective Disorders: An In-The-Wild Study. *ACM Trans. Interact. Intell. Syst.* DOI:https://doi.org/10.1145/3484508 [ACCEPTED]

Devender Kumar, Raju Maharjan, Alban Maxhuni, Helena Dominguez, Anne Frølich, and Jakob E. Bardram. 2021. mCardia: A Context-Aware Ambulatory ECG Collection System for Arrhythmia Screening. *ACM Health* [ACCEPTED]

# Conferences

Raju Maharjan, Darius Adam Rohani, Per Bækgaard, Jakob Bardram, and Kevin Doherty. 2021. Can we talk? Design Implications for the Questionnaire-Driven Self-Report of Health and Wellbeing via Conversational Agent. *CUI 2021 - 3rd Conference on Conversational User Interfaces*. Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Article 5, 1–11. DOI:https://doi.org/10.1145/3469595.3469600

Giovanna Nunes Vilaza, Raju Maharjan, David Coyle, and Jakob Bardram. 2020. Futures for Health Research Data Platforms From the Participants' Perspectives. In *Proceedings of the 11th Nordic Conference on Human-Computer Interaction: Shaping Experiences, Shaping Society (NordiCHI '20)*. Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Article 39, 1–14. DOI:https://doi.org/10.1145/3419249.3420110

## Workshops

Raju Maharjan, Per Bækgaard, and Jakob E. Bardram. 2019. "Hear me out": smart speaker based conversational agent to monitor symptoms in mental health. In *Adjunct Proceedings of the 2019 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing and Proceedings of the 2019 ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computers (UbiComp/ISWC '19 Adjunct)*. Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, 929–933. DOI:https://doi.org/10.1145/3341162.3346270

Raju Maharjan, Per Bækgaard, and Jakob E. Bardram. 2018. Leveraging Multi-modal User-labeled Data for Improved Accuracy in Interpretation of ECG Recordings. In *Proceedings of the 2018 ACM International Joint Conference and 2018 International Symposium on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing and Wearable Computers (UbiComp '18)*. Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, 636–641. DOI:https://doi.org/10.1145/3267305.3267548

# PAPER REVIEWING

2019 – Present ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)
 2021 ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computers (ISWC)

2020 EAI International Conference on Pervasive Computing Technologies for Healthcare

# **COMMUNITY ACTIVITIES**

2019 Student Volunteer, Conference on Ubiquitous, Pervasive and Wearable Computing (Ubicomp)

2018 Summer School, Humanistic HCI, UBISS '18, 9th International UBI Summer School

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

10/2017 - 01/2018	Frontend Developer, Google, CA
03/2015 - 08/2017	UI/UX Engineer, Abbott Point of Care, NJ
08/2013 - 07/2014	Frontend Developer, Harland Clarke, TX
04/2012 - 05/2012	Frontend Developer, HIV/AIDS Services, NYC Human Resource Administration, NY
06/2011 - 01/2012	Director of Technology, Artbox – NYC College of Technology, NY
04/2011 - 01/2012	Web Designer & Developer, NYC College of Technology, NY
11/2009 — 09/2010	Web Developer, IBREA Foundation, NY
11/2009 — 10/2010	Web Developer, Iced Media and Boom Digital Ventures, NY
07/2007 - 05/2008	Technology Mentor, The City University of New York Research Foundation, NY

# **SKILLS**

Prototyping Conversational Agents, Chatbots, Mobile Application, Web Application, 3D Models

Design Dialogflow, Figma, Axure, Illustrator, Photoshop, Indesign, After Effects, Premiere Pro, Maya

Development Javascript, PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL/NoSQL, Java

Research Qualitative, Quantitative & Mixed-Method Study Design, User-Centered Design, Design Thinking,

Participatory Design, Survey, Workshop, Interviews, Focus Groups

Data Analysis Text Mining, Topic Modeling, Data Visualization, Thematic Analysis, R, Python, MS Excel